[Flourished Peony]
[Episode 10]
The purslane
has value,
but it's not nearly as good as the peony.
Looks like we've lost some money
on the medicinal herbs,
but in fact,
it has bought us more time
to profit sooner.
I learned to do business
with my father since I was little.
The first thing I learned was
sometimes,
time is more valuable
than money.
I see.
Shengyi.
Since you had doubts,
why didn't you ask me before?
I don't understand the ways of doing business,
for fear of saying something wrong
and ruining your plan.
I knew it now.
As expected, I'm being shortsighted.
From now on,
I'll do whatever you say.
I won't ask any question again.
Don't say so.
We are partners in business.
We are equals.
If you have any doubts,
just ask me.
Mudan,
you can both read
and do business.
And you said once you've made money,
then you'd buy back your mother's house.
You must be from a wealthy family.
Shengyi.
If we no longer worry about money,
what do you want to do?
Before I got married,
I lived for my parents and siblings.
After I got married,
my husband was my everything.
I've never thought
what I want to do
or what I can do.
Now you are free.
You can do whatever you want.
Have you ever thought about
learning to write?
So, you can read account books
and official documents.
And you will no longer be fooled.
I…
It's too late to learn at this age.
I'm afraid I would make mistakes
to keep accounts by myself.
If I hire another accountant,
it'll cost us a lot,
and I'm worried of being cheated.
Shengyi.
The person I trust most now
is only you.
You are smart and diligent.
Surely you will learn quickly.
Just help me, okay?
Help me.
Then, I hope you
would forgive me for being slow-witted.
Come on, I'll teach you now.
The Jiang Mansion is so lively.
He's having party every night,
not fearing it harmful to health.
I just hope my Qiongtai Yulu
would be placed in a safe spot,
not being knocked or bumped by anyone.
Shengyi.
I'll teach you right now.
Look, when we do the accounting,
it has to be from right to left.
You know about that, right?
[Jiang Mansion]
It must be foolproof.
What I brought this time
is twice as much as the last time.
This time, we would surely succeed.
The Floral Envoy is so unpredictable.
Lady He.
Is today Mr. Jiang's birthday?
Why have so many people come?
No. Today is the fifteenth of the month,
suitable for opening the warehouse.
You would frequently move around here.
I'll take you for a tour.
The merchants
would open the warehouses and move goods.
What are the practices in the Jiang Mansion?
My lord says
since the warehouse door is opened,
we must put something in.
These officials all here
to help fill the warehouse.
Next, please enter the main hall.
My lord's little pet.
Little pet?
A pipa inlaid with gems and seashells.
Such a large scale.
This scale was custom-made by My lord.
If the item doesn't pass this scale,
it can't be presented to My lord.
The gem on this
is worth the annual salary
of a Sixth-Rank official.
Take it slow, slower.
Hold steady.
Come on, weigh it.
Weigh it!
Mr. Feng.
We will not accept it.
Why not?
Didn't you say as long as the item
weighs over a hundred taels,
then one can meet Mr. Jiang?
Your stone is heavy enough,
but your sincerity
is not.
This is red coral…
With such a large rare stone,
and yet his sincerity is still not enough.
I specially had someone
bring it by sea from Qiongzhou.
It took me a lot of trouble.
My sincerity towards Mr. Jiang
is just like this rare stone,
large and bright red.
Mr. Feng.
I think it's because
your sincerity toward others is not enough.
Chuanyu.
Thank you for your hard work.
Why not
do me a favor?
Drink some tea and get relaxed.
This is a real gold lump.
I am a servant of the Jiang Mansion,
completely reliant on My lord
for my livelihood.
This red coral
embodies my sincerity.
If you don't give me a reason for refusal,
I will stay here today.
I will stay here.
In that case,
Mr. Feng, please
bring your sincerity with you and come with me.
What are you waiting for?
Hurry up.
Mr. Feng.
This piece was offered by Mr. Bao,
also transported from Qiongzhou.
Mr. Feng, you'd better
to choose another new item.
And try again on the fifteenth of next month.
Lady He.
The Epang Palace is lined
with ten thousand houses.
There are layers of gates for guarding.
I think that's it.
Mr. Jiang grabbed the tail of the monster tiger
with his left hand.
His right hand just like this.
Shoot three arrows at once
at the monster.
The demon's forehead, chest,
and groin each struck by an arrow.
It died on the spot.
Good, good.
Clouds billowing under Mr. Jiang's feet.
Before I could even react,
Mr. Jiang had already flown before me.
I immediately knelt in worship, saying
"Thank you for saving my life."
But Mr. Jiang said,
"Slaying demons and upholding justice.
Mr. Yin, don't mention it."
But how could I forget your kindness?
Upon waking up,
I immediately asked
the embroidery house to embroider this
"Hero Jiang's Demon-Repelling Picture".
No wonder I haven't been sleeping well.
So I did such a grand deed
in your dream.
This should be acted in a play.
I have already ordered someone to do it.
I'm worried that even with the best actors,
we still can't portray
a fraction of your grace.
I've done such a dashing deed,
yet I don't remember it at all.
What a pity.
However, this matter is quite interesting.
I can tell it to His Majesty.
If His Majesty laughs at me,
you must testify for me.
Of course.
These are a basket of magpie eggs.
The divine bird in the dream
entrusted me to offer them to you.
You even
brought me things from the dream.
Of course, I should give you a return gift.
Well…
You're so nice, Mr. Jiang.
This is a cricket?
His Majesty has recently
indulged in cricket fighting,
so he bestowed this
victorious cricket to me.
It has won twenty battles out of twenty.
If you have nightmares again,
let it slay demons on my behalf.
So I won't have to come to your dream.
This is an object bestowed by His Majesty.
I am so grateful.
The cricket has escaped.
On the fifteenth of next month,
you'll open the warehouse again?
No, we'll move.
Move?
To move the items in the warehouse.
Move those on the left to the right.
And move those on the right to the back.
My lord says
once we move things away,
there will be new space in the warehouse.
Once with the new space,
why not fill it up?
Please.
Your warehouse
is just like Mr. Jiang's desire,
can never be completely filled.
We've spent so much money,
only to get a cricket.
It is quite a loss.
Let me tell you.
This is not just any cricket,
but a message.
If I can cater to His Majesty's preferences
and greatly please him,
then I can secure a position
as the Note-taking Official.
I would then become someone
by the emperor's side.
Mr. Jiang serving as the Floral Envoy
is truly a waste of his talent.
He should go to the Imperial Academy
to impart knowledge and teach.
That would really be
exchanging gold and jade for advices.
It's more valuable than knowledge in books.
But he just betrayed His Majesty
like this,
isn't he afraid of His Majesty's blame?
My lord and His Majesty
have grown up together from childhood,
as close as siblings.
It's just about sharing the fun
among friends.
What a coincidence.
Sharing the fun with others every time
happens to be the fifteen day of the month.
In order to accumulate wealth
with a just cause,
Floral Envoy even
used the auspicious days.
In terms of
using dirty tricks,
he is truly amazing.
I'm impressed.
Lady He, please.
However, I can also use the auspicious days
to sell flowers.
Perhaps it could
take my business to the next level.
My lord.
If you want to steal my unique tricks,
you have to pay me.
Not at all. I wouldn't dare.
I've almost finished touring.
If there's nothing else,
I will go water the plants first.
May you be well.
Wait.
In my mansion,
you speak ill of me to my guard.
How bold you are.
The true base person
would hide
all the filthy thoughts,
just like the family of Liu Chang.
Yet you receive the gifts and never hide it.
And your most trusted guard
tells me everything.
I guess you wish me
to spread it until everyone knows.
In my opinion,
you probably long for
this notoriety,
so you can hide
something else.
I still remember the copper coin
that was shot away.
Don't you want to know
what I am hiding?
Not at all.
I am an ordinary citizen.
Even my household registration
has to be done by the help of you.
How dare I know more?
The Qiongtai Yulu is in the study.
Thank you, Mr. Jiang.
Lady He, please.
This grape wine
is sent from Persia
from a thousand miles away.
County Princess, Zishu.
If the two of you like it,
on your big wedding day,
I will take care of this drink.
Here, everyone.
Let's drink this cup to the full.
Here.
This wine is clear, sweet, refreshing,
quite nice.
Zishu, don't be fooled by him.
He lost a bet with someone,
and spent a fortune
to buy all the grape wine in Chang'an.
He fears that he can't hide it at home
and would be discovered by his father,
so he wants us to help him with it.
Brother.
Prince Ning's Mansion doesn't lack anything.
They couldn't appreciate this fruit wine.
The first time visiting,
I have also brought an item
for you to enjoy.
The work by Master Wu
is magnificent and ingeniously crafted.
A rare piece indeed.
This is one of Master Wu's works
before he became famous,
extremely rare.
It is also treasured
by my father for many years.
I hope you will like it.
Zishu.
Indeed, as County Princess says,
you are elegant and charming.
Even your taste in the calligraphy and painting
is also extraordinary and refined.
You gave me this.
And I must give you something in return.
Master Wu
is skilled at painting people.
Go to the study and bring
"The Portrait of the Child-Giving God".
Yes.
"The Portrait of the Child-Giving God"?
Wasn't it presented
to His Majesty by Master Wu?
How could it be?
They are the founding nobles,
often graced by His Majesty's rewards.
To possess this painting
is not surprised.
Your sincerity is not enough.
We have many Master Wu's paintings.
County Princess,
you accompany Mr. Liu to choose one.
Just take
whatever you like.
His paintings are worth a fortune
and hard to obtain.
The Jia family's collections
did not come easily either.
"The Portrait of the Child-Giving God"
is enough for me.
How dare I take another one?
My father and Master Wu
have been close friends for years,
and our families are also longtime friends.
Zishu, don't be shy.
If the two of you like it,
I will have someone invite him over
to create a new painting
for you both on the spot.
How about that?
That would be great.
What do you think, Zishu?
We have been drinking
in this room the whole time.
It's a bit boring.
Why not go to the side of the agate pool
to play drinking games?
Let's see today
who can leave sober.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
- Come.
Zishu, let's go.
You go ahead first.
We'll go ahead.
Mr. Jia.
I heard you are working
at the Ministry of Works.
Well, I have an essay on water transport
and would like to discuss with you.
We are
born in a wealthy family.
So, we should
live at the moment.
Why discuss it?
The heavy burdens of governing
should be left
to those minor officials
with humble background.
I think the gift I sent
is elegant and refined,
but in fact, they despised on it.
Better not to send it at all.
That Mr. Jia has many fine paintings,
but he doesn't appreciate them.
How can he compare with
your talents and ambitions?
Nobles possess
wealth that others can hardly
accumulate in a lifetime,
yet only seek pleasure,
without any ambition.
Thinking that I will inevitably
have to socialize with them,
making me feel weary.
In the past, only the nobles
could afford peonies.
Thanks to that flower-selling woman,
mow we can afford them too.
This Huaixiuxiang is smaller
than the average peony,
but has full and round flowers.
It's perfect for decorating the house.
Yes, I heard that woman
is from Qingliang Mountain.
My lord.
What does that flower-selling woman look like?
Zishu.
What are you doing here?
He must get drunk
from helping you fend off drinks,
so he came out to take a walk.
The Jia Mansion is too big, so I got lost.
Are you feeling unwell?
After Mr. Liu marries County Princess,
the mansion you will live in
will be much bigger than mine.
By then,
you must stick close to County Princess.
Don't do it like today.
You've only lost for a moment,
and she got so worried.
You!
What are they holding?
Peonies?
Since when did your family
use such inferior goods
to decorate the courtyard?
Why do you get such vulgar things?
We bought these flowers for ourselves.
We were just about to take them
to the servants' room.
Sorry for being seen by you.
We'll take them away now.
Hurry.
Please forgive me.
Zishu, let's go,
lest we get dirtied.
Some people are just like this flower,
incompatible with
this luxurious mansion.
I'll take my leave.
In the past, only the nobles
could afford peonies.
Thanks to that flower-selling woman,
now we can afford them too.
Don't go back yet.
Make a trip to the flower market.
Yes.
Turn right ahead.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Potted peonies should not be watered too much.
- Got it. Understood.
It is not…
We've already pushed the price of the flowers
down to the lowest,
but after deducting the cost
and the bonus to the Floral Envoy,
there isn't much left in the monthly profit.
It's okay. Take it slow.
We will save up more.
Once the flowering period
of this Huaixiuxiang is over,
we'll have to find other low-priced peonies.
We have to keep providing
potted peonies for sale,
then we can retain customers.
Good.
Shengyi, it's still early.
You can go home first.
I'll go check out the florists in the suburbs.
I'll clean up here.
- You go ahead.
- I'm leaving now.
Excuse me.
Do you sell Huaixiuxiang here?
Could this be…?
I paid a lot for this
Fire Gold Peony.
You have to compensate for me.
Well…
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
How much did this flower cost?
Twenty strings.
What?
Twenty strings?
This is literally asking for my life.
You've been deceived.
Go find that swindler.
Don't talk nonsense.
This flower of mine
was worth this price,
but this old fold
- destroyed the flower with his donkey.
- Well…
Please judge.
You have truly been deceived.
Your flower seems nice,
but its stem hasn't grown well at all.
It's a Chinese peony in its first year,
failing to pinch the buds
and causing the insufficient nutrients.
This flower this year
is definitely not going to bloom.
That's strange.
Logically speaking,
a renowned variety like Fire Gold Peony
should be cared for by a gardener.
I understand now. I guess some
servant in the noble mansion
stole this flower
and can't maintain it,
now it won't survive
and they deceived you.
This has nothing to do with you.
Don't talk nonsense here.
- He's deceived by someone.
- Old folk.
Today, you either compensate,
or come with me to the yamen. Come on.
I truly can't pay it.
My lord, don't do this.
To the yamen, right? I'll go with you.
I'll be a witness.
The swindler is so despicable,
stealing flowers and deceiving for money.
He must be at least punished
with fifty heavy beatings.
Forget it, old folk.
You are advanced in age.
I won't make it difficult for you.
Just give me three strings,
and let's settle this privately.
I don't even have three strings.
No way. We can't let the swindle go.
Let's go to the yamen.
There's no need for that.
We must punish the swindle.
I-I have urgent matters to attend to.
My wife is about to give birth soon,
she's waiting for me at home.
Is that so?
Otherwise, you sell this flower to me.
Consider it me being swindled.
I will go look for the swindler with him,
if we can't,
I'll just accept my bad luck.
Well…
But right now,
I only have this much money.
Just this?
Right, you've spent twenty strings.
Forget it, let's go to the yamen.
Let's go. To report to the yamen.
No need.
Alright, I'm having bad luck.
Come on, hurry up.
The swindler is himself.
Right.
You haven't said who the swindler is yet.
Sir, the swindler is himself.
I just saw with my own eyes
that he injured your donkey.
He's putting on this act just to fool you.
I see.
My lord.
Do you think
that the woman selling flowers
is Young Madam?
I've always felt
she wouldn't disappear
from this world that easily.
But the Buyao at the edge of the cliff
indeed belongs to her.
I know.
Towards Young Madam…
He Weifang
had been married to me for a year,
and I only realized
what kind of person she really was
until the last few days,
and how the Liu family have failed her.
I used to be indifferent to her.
I really intended to make amends.
What a pity.
There's no opportunity anymore.
I'm fine.
Thank you for helping me.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
- Okay.
- After you.
Take it slow.
He Weifang.
Wait.
- Let go of me.
- He Weifang.
- Why do you run upon seeing me?
Why did you pretend to die?
I am dead.
Is that not just
what the Liu family wished for?
That was my parents' wish,
not what I wished for.
Your parents could take possession of my dowry.
You could marry County Princess.
And I could start afresh
with a new identity.
Liu Chang.
I'm begging you.
Please show mercy and spare me.
Start afresh?
Is this what situation you are in?
Disheveled and in a sorry state.
How have you been spending your days?
Have you been working as a servant for someone?
I have my own means of livelihood.
Don't worry about me.
Are you selling flowers?
So the flower-selling woman is really you.
For the Liu family,
I had to marry County Princess.
But I am not a person
who's not ungrateful and abandon his wife.
Liu Chang.
From beginning to end,
we were never truly husband and wife.
And now we have already divorced.
Why would you rather
be a lowly flower merchant,
rather than returning to me?
If there were no merchants or farmers,
where would the clothes you wear,
the things you use at home
come from?
I earn money with my own effort.
I have never felt that I am lowly.
That's not what I mean.
Now I have seen you clearly.
I misunderstood you in the past.
He Weifang.
Can you calm down
and get to know me again?
I did not sign the divorce agreement.
As long as you are willing to…
Liu Chang.
I wanted to
leave you some dignity.
But you are relentless,
and I really can't stand it.
Your parents coveted my dowry,
and even sent someone to kill me.
They forced my father to abandon me,
leaving me with no home to return to.
You used fake medicine
to deceive me into marrying you,
causing me to miss the opportunity
to treat my mother,
leading to her untimely death.
Between you and me,
except for hatred,
there is no other possibility.
Your mother passed away from illness.
This is really my Liu family's fault.
I can't deny it.
But, I was unaware.
If you are willing now,
I can steal the Zixi pill for you.
Whether you keep it, or take it…
My mother has already died.
Why do I want this Zixi pill?
Liu Chang.
Whatever you have done,
to me, it is all the same.
My mother
has gone.
He Weifang.
- What are you going to do?
- Listen to me.
Whatever the Liu family and I have done,
I admit all of it.
Give me a chance to make amends.
I can take good care of you for your mother.
I know you like to grow flowers,
so I can arrange a garden for you.
You no longer need to be looked down upon,
worry about making a living,
work hard day and night.
You can live an easy life.
What do you take me for?
A kept woman?
Liu Chang.
This is what you call seeing me clearly?
That's not what I mean.
I just want to protect you well.
I don't want you to face the difficulties
from my parents and County Princess.
If you really want to protect me,
then don't tell anyone that I am still alive,
or appear in front of me again.
Excuse me.
Come on.
He Weifang.
When we married, you were unwilling,
and so were I.
Now He Weifang is dead,
and you are free as well.
Do not bother me anymore.
He Weifang.
She is not dead.
Don't worry.
Rest assured.
Annoying Liu Chang, Liu Chang is annoying.
I was totally
wrong about her
and underestimated her.
She comes from a merchant family,
yet she possesses integrity,
with extraordinary insight.
Just like me,
we all want to make our name by our own.
It's just a pity
that it took me so long to realize.
Shuai.
Do I really have no chance to make amends?
I like Mudan.
What am I doing?
What do you like about her?
Her defiant coldness,
her hostility in words,
or her situation
of being free and unrestrained?
He dared to deceive
an old person in the street!
That person is truly shameless.
Yes. So,
I just came forward
and lent the old person a hand.
So I got this.
Shengyi.
This peony is really Fire Gold Peony.
If we could save it,
then this pot
could fetch a sky-high price.
Right. Go buy some mangrove bark.
Use it to soak in water and water the flowers.
It can promote rooting.
Go ahead.
Mr. Third, let's drink.
I won.
Drink.
I'm not playing anymore. I lose anyway.
Mr. Pan, you'll have to drink this for me.
No cheating.
The lead courtesan of Huanyun Tower
played the wrong note,
yet didn't notice it?
I'm sorry
that I distracted
by the beauty kites in the sky.
Please forgive me.
You distracted
by such little kites?
Bring over my kite.
Yes.
Let me show you
how to overshadow the sky.
- Good.
Is this a phoenix? It's truly exquisite.
I've never seen
such a big kite.
- Right?
- Look.
Are these feathers real?
- You guess.
- I don't know.
- Mr. Third.
As a man with a wife,
competing with us for the ladies' affection.
You!
- Exactly.
- Alright.
I'm just tired of holding it.
- Come on. Help me.
- You have a good taste.
Yesterday, I played polo with you,
and now my left arms sore.
Fly your own phoenix kite yourself.
Stop nagging, lest you complain about it.
Take it.
- It has flown away.
- The kite has flown away.
The kite has flown away.
It has flown to the backyard.
It took
two months to make this kite.
Now,
it's all in the Jiang Mansion.
Just send someone to pick it up.
That wine-making backyard
has been neglected for years.
Inside it's all tattered and torn.
Even if picked up, it would be dirty.
Forget it.
Now that the courtyard has been taken care of.
Someone lives there.
Who?
Just a peasant girl who grows flowers.
The kite that the corrupt official flies
is so extravagant and wasteful.
These feathers
all came from the bonus
I gave him.
Suizhi, you are hiding a beauty here?
Then I must go take a look.
She's just renting here.
I'm not hiding her.
Besides, there is a door bolt.
You can't just go in.
Mr. Third.
Suizhi.
Come down, Mr. Third.
Mr. Third.
Come down.
What are you doing?
You just twisted your waist
playing polo yesterday,
yet you're still messing around here.
You've played among women for so many years,
and it's the first time
you brought a woman home.
I must see who she is.
Just right, support me.
Wait, what? Leave.
Stop it. I'll just take a glance.
- Just one glance.
- Hurry, support me.
Come on. Take it slow.
Hold on tight!
- Wait.
- Take it slow.
- Harder.
- Grab onto it firmly.
Harder.
Terrible.
- Jiang Changyang.
This Fire Gold Peony of mine
is extremely precious.
Smashed just like that by your friend,
its stems have all broken.
I'm afraid it's likely doomed.
I demand compensation from you.
That's not too much to ask, right?
Well…
The Fire Gold Peony
is very difficult to care for,
with a low survival rate.
Even without today's incident,
you might not have been able
to grow it successfully.
It was you who failed
to keep an eye on your friend,
how come you are questioning me?
You're the one making outrageous demands first,
of course, I would question you.
- You!
- What?
This flower woman is quite attractive,
but why is she money-grubbing?
Having such a good opportunity…
No wonder Suizhi wouldn't let us see.
She's quite vulgar.
However, the scene where Mr. Third smashed
into the flowers was indeed rare to witness.
Tomorrow I'll have to talk about it to Mr. Jia.
Furthermore, no one knows
if it's the real Fire Gold Peony,
or fake.
Mr. Jiang, in order to shrink your blame,
you really can beat around the bush.
You are usually so generous
to those beauties.
Why are you unwilling
to be generous for your friend?
Sir, you've made a bad friend.
Now that you see who he really is,
- you must feel quite upset.
- You!
What? Stop it.
Maybe I'll say something.
Alright. Go ahead.
May I know your name?
Don't be that polite.
The person who named me
fell seriously ill.
I fear my humble name
would not be pleasant to your ears.
You may call me Mudan.
Mudan.
May I know you name?
What a coincidence. My name
is also not very pleasant to the ear.
I am the third in my family.
Lady Mudan, you may call me Mr. Third.
Mr. Third. I'm not being fussing.
We run a small-scale business,
and this smash from you is so disastrous.
I am the one who broke the flower,
so I should be the one to compensate.
Suizhi defended me
just out of fear that I would be at a loss.
Lady Mudan, don't be mad at him.
I am willing to place an order for this flower.
If you can truly grow
the Fire Gold Peony,
no matter the price,
I will buy it.
But if you can't,
then you have no proof.
At that time, I will compensate
according to the price of ordinary flowers
to you. How does that sound?
Mr. Third, you are truly reasonable,
not like someone.
If that's the case,
I am willing to draft an agreement,
lest someone accuses me of extortion.
You are so magnanimous,
certainly will not refuse
sign the agreement.
You are afraid he will deny the debt.
Do you think your friends would deny the debt?
Of course not.
Right, Mr. Third?
Wuniang.
Wuniang, do not be afraid.
I am here to buy flowers.
Huaixiuxiang, eighty wens per pot.
Seeing that you are doing well now,
I can rest assured.
What do you want?
Wuniang, come back to me.
I lost my soul after you left.
Nothing feels meaningful.
The newly hired helpers are even so lazy.
And the tavern's business
gets worse day by day.
Without you, I really can't live on.
It was you who wanted to sell me.
I was just so furious,
and wanted to scare you.
I didn't want to sell you.
It's all because of Mudan.
She instigated the nobles to pressure me.
I really had no choice.
Wuniang, I miss you so much.
Wuniang.
I really miss you so much.
She is not Qin Wuniang.
- So many people here.
- I truly can't leave…
Let her go.
You are no longer Qin Wuniang.
You are Qin Shengyi.
Don't fear that man anymore.
♫ In endless Chang'an,
the zither's melody distant ♫
♫ Plum and willow trees bask in the sunshine,
as splendor returns with the year ♫
♫ Copper palace battlements,
songs and dances, glass goblets ♫
♫ Idle clouds and duckweed,
a thousand flowers burst forth ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫
♫ The distant night sky strewn with stars,
reflecting the lovely moon ♫
♫ The peony's magnificent beauty
fills the fragrant garden ♫
♫ With a heart as my lantern,
I don't mind the distant mountain paths ♫
♫ The flute's sound,
a fleeting life's wishes fulfilled ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫